

Profile

Having 10 years of experience in the field of web development.

Technical skills include HTML5, CSS3, SASS, JavaScript, jQuery, Angular JS and React JS.

Well versed knowledge on solving the cross browser compatibility issues both Web and Mobile platforms.

Monitors progress of own work and teams work and reports on discrepancies.

Establishes good working relationship with customers, end users, internal and external customers etc.

Proven ability in quick understanding and learning of new technologies and their application in business solutions.

Participate and give feedback in design and code reviews with other developers.

Employment History

Web designer at Imaginet Ventures, Chennai

April 2011 — April 2013

Creating PSD templates, banners and Buttons. Converting PSD to HTML conversion using HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Javascript and using RWD

Web designer at Fortunesoft IT Innovations, Bangalore

August 2013 — July 2016

Analyze the specications provided by the clients. Worked closely with a team that consisted of Design, QA Specialists and backend engineers. Developed websites for customers that are mobile responsive designs.

Senior Software Engineer at Tech Mahindra Ltd , Bangalore

July 2016 — November 2021

Ensure team meets delivery timelines with development and testing perspective, Establish and maintain agreed standards for the teams work. Ensure coding standards, code reviews are followed for Development work. Closely worked with the Business Development teams in order to provide website quality. Provides advice and guidance to less experienced colleagues where required.

Education

B.Tech (Information Technology), Anna University, Chengalpattu

May 2005 — May 2010

Details

+49 15129422996 venkypsd@gmail.com

Skills

HTML5

CSS3

SASS

Bootstrap

JavaScript

Git

jQuery

AngularJS

React JS

Hobbies

Cricket, Football, Reading

Languages

Tamil

English

German